dart a type safe general purpose programming language designed for
dart 一种类型安全的通用编程语言，旨在
building fast apps on multiple platforms it was developed by google and first
在多个平台上构建快速应用程序，由谷歌开发并
appeared in 2011 and was intended to be an alternative to javascript by shipping
于 2011 年首次出现，旨在通过
its own virtual machine to run apps in the browser but things got off to a
提供自己的虚拟机在浏览器中运行应用程序来替代 javascript，但事情得到了
rocky start and it was never really embraced by the web development
起步并不顺利，它从未真正被 Web 开发社区所接受，
community however it bounced back in a big way after being adopted by the
但在被 Flutter 框架采用后，它又大幅反弹
flutter framework and today it's one of the most loved programming languages in
，如今它是业内最受欢迎的编程语言
the industry it's unique for its ability to compile to multiple targets like arm
之一，它的独特之处在于它能够 编译为多个目标，例如
and x64 machine code for mobile devices javascript for web browsers and
移动设备的 arm 和 x64 机器代码用于 Web 浏览器的 JavaScript 和
self-contained executables for windows mac os and linux it also has a just in
Windowsmac os 和 linux 的自包含可执行文件 它还有一个
time or jit compiler which compiles your source code to machine code on the fly
即时编译器或 jit 编译器，可将您的源代码即时编译为机器代码
which can boost developer productivity with features like hot reload and
， 可以通过热重载和
flutter all dark code runs inside of an isolate which is like a chunk of memory
颤动等功能提高开发人员的生产力 k 内存
running a single threaded event loop this makes it possible to perform
运行单线程事件循环，这使得
asynchronous background work on a single thread but you can also spawn multiple
在单个线程上执行异步后台工作成为可能，但您也可以生成多个
isolates to run code in parallel the language itself is type safe which means
隔离以并行运行代码语言本身是类型安全的，这
that a variable's value always matches its static type and that generally
意味着变量的值始终与其静态匹配 类型，这通常
results in fewer runtime errors for your app in production however the type
会在生产中为您的应用程序减少运行时错误，但是类型
system is flexible allowing you to use dynamic types and runtime checks when
系统很灵活，允许您在需要时使用动态类型和运行时检查
required it also provides null safety which means that values can't be null
，它还提供空值安全性，这意味着值不能为空，
unless you explicitly allow them to be which can further cut down runtime
除非您明确允许它们 在语法上，它可以进一步减少运行时
exceptions syntactically it's often described as combining elements of java
异常，它通常被描述为结合 java
and javascript a dart program always starts with a main function that has no
和 javascript 的元素一个 dart 程序总是以一个没有返回值的 main 函数开始，
return value so it's annotated with the void type inside of it we might declare
所以它内部带有 void 类型的注释，我们可以声明
a variable with var and set it equal to a string dart will automatically infer
一个变量 var 并将其设置为字符串 dart 会自动将其
this as a string type however we could explicitly type it by replacing var
推断为字符串类型，但是我们可以解释 citly 通过替换 var 来输入它
anything you can store in a variable is an object and every object is an
你可以存储在变量中的任何东西都是一个对象，每个对象都是
instance of a class the only thing that's not an object in dart is null
一个类的实例dart 中唯一不是对象的东西是 null
this opens the door to multiple programming paradigms functions are also
这为多种编程范式打开了大门 函数也是
first-class objects which means they can be passed around for functional
一流的 对象，这意味着它们可以被传递以进行函数式
programming or you can define classes with mixin-based inheritance for
编程，或者您可以为面向对象模式定义具有基于 mixin 的继承的类，
object-oriented patterns on top of that it has a package manager called pub
除此之外它有一个名为 pub 的包管理器，
providing thousands of open source packages to help you get things done
提供数千个开源包来帮助您完成
this has been dart in 100 seconds hit the like button and subscribe if you
这项工作 已经在 100 秒内完成了 dart，如果你
want to see more short videos like this and if you want to get really good at
想看更多这样的短视频，点击喜欢按钮并订阅，如果你想真正擅长
dart i just released a brand new full course for pro members it teaches the
dart，我刚刚为专业会员发布了一个全新的完整课程，它教授
fundamentals of dart from the ground up to get you ready for flutter development
dart 的基础知识为 Flutter 开发
and my upcoming flutter 2 course which will be out later this year thanks for
和我即将在今年晚些时候推出的 Flutter 2 课程做好准备感谢
watching and i will see you in the next one
您的观看，我们下期再见